<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Crappy Code Blog</title>
    <description>Watch me code stuff... poorly</description>
    <link>http://eshapard.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eshapard.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Order To Learn Spanish Conjugations According To Word Frequency Data</title>
        <description>
          
          If you want to tackle Spanish verb conjugation in an order that goes from most common uses to least common uses, and in an order that gradually builds your knowledge using the smallest increments possible, I think the curriculum below may be what you’re looking for. Note: These suggestions are...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/learning/anki/best-order-to-learn-spanish-conjugations-according-to-word-frequency-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/learning/anki/best-order-to-learn-spanish-conjugations-according-to-word-frequency-data.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poorly Named, But Good Anki Addon</title>
        <description>
          
          Just ran across a reference to this cryptically named addon today: Another Retreat It sets the new interval after a lapse to whatever the interval was before the one that led to a lapse. This is a nice way of solving the problem of finding a decent post-lapse interval. Be...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/poorly-named,-but-good-anki-addon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/poorly-named,-but-good-anki-addon.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Separate Taskwarrior Configuration For Ideas</title>
        <description>
          
          Task warrior has a lot of filtering options, but it’s faster to keep your ideas (or someday/maybes as they call them in Getting Things Done) completely separate. That way, you can see only the tasks you’re actually working on without cluttering up your task list wit the ideas you have...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/code/a-separate-taskwarrior-configuration-for-ideas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/code/a-separate-taskwarrior-configuration-for-ideas.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Applying Spaced Repetition To Online Course Design</title>
        <description>
          
          I got a private message from someone who’s developing an online learning platform for an after-school program. The idea is to incorporate spacing techniques in the lessons themselves while incorporating feedback from the student to try to hit an 80-90% success rate (as I advocate elsewhere in this blog). I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/applying-spaced-repetition-to-online-course-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/applying-spaced-repetition-to-online-course-design.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self-Destructing Emails With Not-Much Mail</title>
        <description>
          
          I use offlineimap + not-much mail + astroid to handle my email and I wanted a way to make emails self-destruct after a certain amount of time. Here’s the script I came up with to do that: nmExpire.py #!/usr/bin/python import notmuch import re, datetime from dateutil.relativedelta import relativedelta #from pprint...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/python/self-destructing-emails-with-not-much-mail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/python/self-destructing-emails-with-not-much-mail.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Put Not-Much Emails To Sleep</title>
        <description>
          
          I’ve been using not-much mail in combination with offlineimap and astroid (as the front-end) to handle my email. I wanted to implement a very useful function that I use with outlook for my work email: putting emails to sleep for a time and having them wake up automatically. Basically, if...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/python/put-not-much-emails-to-sleep.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/python/put-not-much-emails-to-sleep.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Export Taskwarrior Dates To Remind</title>
        <description>
          
          I’ve been playing around with the geeky, efficient, command-line scheduling program remind. It’s very cool once you get used to it. I wanted to automatically export any duedates from taskwarrior, so this is what I came up with. Export Taskwarrior Dates I found a script that did this (written in...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/export-taskwarrior-dates-to-remind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/export-taskwarrior-dates-to-remind.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quickly View I3Wm Hotkeys</title>
        <description>
          
          Use the code below to quickly view all the active hotkeys in your i3wm config file: i3keys #!/bin/bash grep &quot;^[ ]*bindsym&quot; ~/.i3/config | sed -e 's/^[ ]*bindsym //' -e 's/^[ ]*$mod/win/' | less Background i3wm has a lot of functions that come assigned to hotkeys by default. I’m constantly forgetting...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/quickly-view-i3wm-hotkeys.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/quickly-view-i3wm-hotkeys.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Short Python Scripts For Tomboy Notes</title>
        <description>
          
          OK, here are two more scripts I wrote to do useful things with python and Tomboy notes. tbclip This first one copies whatever text is currently selected and creates a Tomboy note with it. NB: You must have xclip installed. #!/usr/bin/python import sys, dbus, subprocess #Get the D-Bus session bus...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/two-short-python-scripts-for-tomboy-notes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/two-short-python-scripts-for-tomboy-notes.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Display Your Most Recent Tomboy Note</title>
        <description>
          
          This is a handy little script I came up with. It displays the most recently modified Tomboy note. This is helpful if, like me, you make pull up a new Tomboy note for something quick and then accidentally close it by hitting escape or something. Creating a hot-key for this...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/display-your-most-recent-tomboy-note.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/display-your-most-recent-tomboy-note.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delete Old Uncategorized Tomboy Notes From Cron</title>
        <description>
          
          I read an article about using python and dbus to automate some stuff with Tomboy Notes and was inspired to do some coding of my own. In a Nutshell Use the code below (and a cron job) to automatically delete Tomboy notes that were last modified more than 30 days...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/delete-old-uncategorized-tomboy-notes-from-cron.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/delete-old-uncategorized-tomboy-notes-from-cron.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache Webserver No Longer Runs Php After Upgrade To Ubuntu 18</title>
        <description>
          
          The fix See code below The story Upgraded to Ubuntu 18 and the webserver broke. Something always breaks when you upgrade. This time, it was my webserver… just like last time All the packages were installed, but turns out, the Apache php7.2 module needed to be enabled. sudo a2enmod php7.2...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/apache-webserver-no-longer-runs-php-after-upgrade-to-ubuntu-18.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/apache-webserver-no-longer-runs-php-after-upgrade-to-ubuntu-18.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anki - Dynamic Efficient Learning Steps With Feedback</title>
        <description>
          
          Use the average ease of mature cards as feedback to generate efficient learning steps for new cards. Udate 2018-03-14: Addon coded; see bottom of page. In a Nutshell Create 5 learning steps for each deck with steps 3-5 based on the initial ease factor of the deck (which is set...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-learning-steps-with-feedback.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-learning-steps-with-feedback.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache Webserver No Longer Runs Php After Upgrade To Ubuntu 17.10</title>
        <description>
          
          The fix See code below The story I recently upgraded to 17.10 after I started to get 404 errors when trying to install packages. Yeah, I should upgrade more often, but something always breaks when you upgrade. This time, it was my webserver. All the packages were installed, but turns...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/apache-webserver-no-longer-runs-php-after-upgrade-to-ubuntu-17.10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/apache-webserver-no-longer-runs-php-after-upgrade-to-ubuntu-17.10.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anki - Auto Adjust New Cards per Day to Meet a Deadline</title>
        <description>
          
          A lot of students use Anki to study for an up-coming exam. And in that case, you want to make sure that you see all the new cards by some arbitrary deadline (leaving ample review time before the exam). Conceptually, it’s easy to adjust the new cards per day setting...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-auto-adjust-new-cards-per-day-to-meet-a-deadline.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-auto-adjust-new-cards-per-day-to-meet-a-deadline.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Send Firefox Tabs To Another Computer</title>
        <description>
          
          I right-clicked on one of my tabs in firefox to close all the tabs to the right and noticed an new option.

There was an option to send the tab to the firefox running on my other computer.

This is super cool/useful.

        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/blog/send-firefox-tabs-to-another-computer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/blog/send-firefox-tabs-to-another-computer.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Current Anki Deck Settings</title>
        <description>
          
          In a nutshell Here are the settings I currently use for most of my decks: New Cards Steps: 15 2160 10080 40320 Order: Show new cards in order added New cards/day: varies Graduating Interval: 45 days Easy Interval: 4 days (not used; I don’t use the easy button anymore) Starting...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/my-current-anki-deck-settings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/my-current-anki-deck-settings.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anki And The Hidden Dangers Of Filtered Decks</title>
        <description>
          
          In a Nutshell If you move a card in the learning queue into or out of a filtered deck (including by rebuilding or deleting the deck), then Anki will set all learning cards to new status and re-learning cards back to review status. While not quite a fix, you can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-and-the-hidden-dangers-of-filtered-decks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-and-the-hidden-dangers-of-filtered-decks.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anki - The Power of Making New Cards on the Fly</title>
        <description>
          
          OK, so you’ve found Anki and started using it, or you’ve used it for a long time and you’re taking advantage of the efficiency of spaced repetition. Maybe you’ve studied Piotr Wozniak’s “20 Rules” article, so you’re formatting your cards well too. But how do you handle leeches? How do...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/the-power-of-making-new-cards-on-the-fly-in-anki.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/the-power-of-making-new-cards-on-the-fly-in-anki.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anki Auto-Adjust New Interval After A Lapse</title>
        <description>
          
          In a nutshell The code below will loop through each of your deck options groups, find the success rate for post-lapse reviews, and attempt to adjust the Lapse New Interval percentage to hit an 85% average success rate. Background Previously, I wrote about using efficient settings for the new interval...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-auto-adjust-new-interval-after-a-lapse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/anki-auto-adjust-new-interval-after-a-lapse.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
