<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Crappy Code Blog</title>
    <description>Watch me code stuff... poorly</description>
    <link>http://eshapard.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eshapard.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Evapotraspiration Rates To Calculate How Much To Water</title>
        <description>
          
          Evapotraspiration (ETo) rates are handy figures you can use to estimate how long to turn on your sprinklers or drip irrigation. Unfortunately, most guides I’ve see either assume you have a degree in agriculture (and don’t really need instruction), or are completely clueless (so they dumb things down too much)....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/code/using-evapotraspiration-rates-to-calculate-how-much-to-water.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/code/using-evapotraspiration-rates-to-calculate-how-much-to-water.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Missing Intro Screen For Gargoyle Interactive Fiction</title>
        <description>
          
          Gargoyle, the interactive fiction interpreter, doesn’t support showing the little introduction screen that glulxe does; the screen with cover art and a description of the game. So I wrote my own quick-and-dirty shell script to do just that. You can use it as sort of a wrapper to start gargoyle....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/missing-intro-screen-for-gargoyle-interactive-fiction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/missing-intro-screen-for-gargoyle-interactive-fiction.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Memory Tests And Their Implications For Flashcard Applications</title>
        <description>
          
          In a nutshell Rationale Desirable difficulty The four memory tests New material Managing new-material workload ‘Learned’ material Maintaining a lower recall ability Python wordfreq and the zipf score Upon failure Got it wrong (Interference) The confusion card No Clue Ways to test memory in detail Recall Aided Recall Recognition Relearning...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/learning/the-4-memory-tests-and-their-implications-for-flashcard-applications.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/learning/the-4-memory-tests-and-their-implications-for-flashcard-applications.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Esperanto &quot;Community&quot; Sucks</title>
        <description>
          
          I studied Esperanto for a couple years and regret it. I don’t consider it a total loss, but I would have gotten more out of studying Spanish, Italian, or French. There are many reasons I regret wasting my time studying Esperanto. Here’s one no one talks about much: Esperanto attracts...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/language/the-esperanto-community-sucks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/language/the-esperanto-community-sucks.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Score Nested Cloze Deletions When You Remember The Parent</title>
        <description>
          
          First read my article about Overlapping and Nested Clozes. If you have nested clozes such as: Cloze 1: In 14[...], Columbus Sailed the Ocean Blue (answer: 92) and Cloze 2: In [...], Columbus Sailed the Ocean Blue (answer: 1492) Then remembering cloze 2 means that you remembered cloze 1 as...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/learning/score-nested-cloze-deletions-when-you-remember-the-parent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/learning/score-nested-cloze-deletions-when-you-remember-the-parent.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set Your Background To Flat Black At Sunset</title>
        <description>
          
          Use sunwait in your crontab to wait until sunset and then run hsetroot to change your desktop. Crontab example: 0 16 * * * sunwait wait set; hsetroot -solid &quot;#000000&quot; Configure and Make Sunwait git clone https://github.com/risacher/sunwait Now edit sunwait.h and replace the default latitude and longitude with whatever your...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/set-your-background-to-flat-black-at-sunset.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/set-your-background-to-flat-black-at-sunset.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haircut Recurrence With Task Warrior</title>
        <description>
          
          To recur a task X days after the last time it was completed, use the task-relative-recur extension by JensErat. I call this ‘haircut’ recurrence because you need to get your hair cut when it’s had enough time to grow long; not on the first of each month. Here’s the problem...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/commandline/haircut-recurrence-with-task-warrior.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/commandline/haircut-recurrence-with-task-warrior.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need To Know About 'Remind' But The Documentation Doesn't Tell You</title>
        <description>
          
          This is the paragraph that’s missing from the introduction of remind’s man page, and every article I’ve ever read about it. If there are timed reminders for later in the day, then remind will continue running in the background, sending timed reminders to the terminal at their appointed times. So...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/what-you-need-to-know-about-remind-but-the-documentation-doesnt-tell-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/what-you-need-to-know-about-remind-but-the-documentation-doesnt-tell-you.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Case For Multiple Goals</title>
        <description>
          
          A useful flashcard application would allow users to set different goals for different cards, control the way cards are prioritized during review sessions, and code custom scheduling and prioritizing algorithms. Furthermore, it would be very useful to purposely design the application to allow for experimental data generation and collection if...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/learning/the-case-for-multiple-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/learning/the-case-for-multiple-goals.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overlapping and Nested Clozes</title>
        <description>
          
          Being able to use overlapping and nested cloze deletions is super useful in a flashcard application. It’s something that I felt was sorely missing from the flashcard applications that I’ve used. [These are overlapping] cloze deletions These are [overlapping cloze deletions] And these are [nested] cloze deletions And these [are...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/learning/code/python/overlapping-clozes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/learning/code/python/overlapping-clozes.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ideas For A Good Flashcard Or Review Application</title>
        <description>
          
          These are some ideas I have for creating a usable flashcard program. They are somewhat organized by topic, but not placed in any particular order. This is sort of a brain-dump for me. I wanted to get these idea out of my head and written down. Some of these ideas...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/learning/anki/ideas-for-a-good-flashcard-or-review-application.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/learning/anki/ideas-for-a-good-flashcard-or-review-application.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Order To Learn Spanish Conjugations According To Word Frequency Data</title>
        <description>
          
          If you want to tackle Spanish verb conjugation in an order that goes from most common uses to least common uses, and in an order that gradually builds your knowledge using the smallest increments possible, I think the curriculum below may be what you’re looking for. Spanish Verb Conjugation Learning...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/learning/anki/best-order-to-learn-spanish-conjugations-according-to-word-frequency-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/learning/anki/best-order-to-learn-spanish-conjugations-according-to-word-frequency-data.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poorly Named, But Good Anki Addon</title>
        <description>
          
          Just ran across a reference to this cryptically named addon today: Another Retreat It sets the new interval after a lapse to whatever the interval was before the one that led to a lapse. This is a nice way of solving the problem of finding a decent post-lapse interval. Be...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/anki/poorly-named,-but-good-anki-addon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/anki/poorly-named,-but-good-anki-addon.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Separate Taskwarrior Configuration For Ideas</title>
        <description>
          
          Task warrior has a lot of filtering options, but it’s faster to keep your ideas (or someday/maybes as they call them in Getting Things Done) completely separate. That way, you can see only the tasks you’re actually working on without cluttering up your task list wit the ideas you have...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/code/a-separate-taskwarrior-configuration-for-ideas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/code/a-separate-taskwarrior-configuration-for-ideas.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Applying Spaced Repetition To Online Course Design</title>
        <description>
          
          I got a private message from someone who’s developing an online learning platform for an after-school program. The idea is to incorporate spacing techniques in the lessons themselves while incorporating feedback from the student to try to hit an 80-90% success rate (as I advocate elsewhere in this blog). I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/applying-spaced-repetition-to-online-course-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/teaching/applying-spaced-repetition-to-online-course-design.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self-Destructing Emails With Not-Much Mail</title>
        <description>
          
          I use offlineimap + not-much mail + astroid to handle my email and I wanted a way to make emails self-destruct after a certain amount of time. Here’s the script I came up with to do that: nmExpire.py #!/usr/bin/python import notmuch import re, datetime from dateutil.relativedelta import relativedelta #from pprint...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/python/self-destructing-emails-with-not-much-mail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/python/self-destructing-emails-with-not-much-mail.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Put Not-Much Emails To Sleep</title>
        <description>
          
          I’ve been using not-much mail in combination with offlineimap and astroid (as the front-end) to handle my email. I wanted to implement a very useful function that I use with outlook for my work email: putting emails to sleep for a time and having them wake up automatically. Basically, if...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/python/put-not-much-emails-to-sleep.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/python/put-not-much-emails-to-sleep.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Export Taskwarrior Dates To Remind</title>
        <description>
          
          I’ve been playing around with the geeky, efficient, command-line scheduling program remind. It’s very cool once you get used to it. I wanted to automatically export any duedates from taskwarrior, so this is what I came up with. Export Taskwarrior Dates I found a script that did this (written in...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/export-taskwarrior-dates-to-remind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/export-taskwarrior-dates-to-remind.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quickly View I3Wm Hotkeys</title>
        <description>
          
          Use the code below to quickly view all the active hotkeys in your i3wm config file: i3keys #!/bin/bash grep &quot;^[ ]*bindsym&quot; ~/.i3/config | sed -e 's/^[ ]*bindsym //' -e 's/^[ ]*$mod/win/' | less Background i3wm has a lot of functions that come assigned to hotkeys by default. I’m constantly forgetting...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/quickly-view-i3wm-hotkeys.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/quickly-view-i3wm-hotkeys.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Short Python Scripts For Tomboy Notes</title>
        <description>
          
          OK, here are two more scripts I wrote to do useful things with python and Tomboy notes. tbclip This first one copies whatever text is currently selected and creates a Tomboy note with it. NB: You must have xclip installed. #!/usr/bin/python import sys, dbus, subprocess #Get the D-Bus session bus...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://eshapard.github.io/linux/two-short-python-scripts-for-tomboy-notes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eshapard.github.io/linux/two-short-python-scripts-for-tomboy-notes.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
